Guide to the Richard Dunlop collection on Vietnam War-era Protests, 1959-1986 MS2176
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Richard Dunlop collection on Vietnam War-era Protests
1959-1986
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Dunlop, Richard E.
MS2176
9 Linear Feet
Collection contains papers, images, sound recordings, and memorabilia related to various social issues, including the Vietnam War, civil rights, women's rights, poverty, communism, and the environment. The material dates from 1959-86, and documents protest activities in the Washington, DC area and other parts of the United States.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Richard Dunlop in 2004. A number of books were included with this donation. They have been separated from the manuscript materials and are now housed in the book collection.
Biographical Note
Richard E. Dunlop was active in the anti-Vietnam war and civil rights movements of the 1960's and 1970's. He is a retired federal administrative judge.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains papers, images, sound recordings, and memorabilia related to various social issues, including the Vietnam War, civil rights, women's rights, poverty, communism, and the environment. The material dates from 1959-86, and documents protest activities in the Washington, DC area and other parts of the United States. The papers form the bulk of the collection, and include flyers, newsletters, reports, government documents, pamphlets, posters, stickers, schedules, calendars, ticket stubs, and sheet music. The materials contain information about both the political and moral objections to war and support of social causes, as well as information about specific protests, marches, sit-ins and other events. The collection also contains photographs and slides of protest demonstrations and recordings of talks on the subjects of pacifism and civil rights. The collection contains a large number of buttons with slogans advocating peace and civil rights.
The term papers used as folder titles refers to documents such as flyers, newsletters, reports, government documents, pamphlets, posters, stickers, schedules, calendars, ticket stubs, and sheet music.
Race relations; Civil rights movements; Civil rights; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975; Human ecology; Poverty; Photographs; Student movements; Protest movements; Demonstrations; Color slides; Women's rights; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements -- United States; Washington (D.C.); Sound recordings; United States. National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders; Pentagon (Va.)--Demonstrations
- Papers, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Papers, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Papers, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Papers, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Papers, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Papers, 1967 [1/2] (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Papers, 1967 [2/2] (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Papers--National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders--Staff and personnel, 07/1967-08/1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Papers--National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders--Testimony, 09/1967-10/1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Papers--National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders--Misc newsletters [News releases] [1/2], 07/1967-12/1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Papers--National Advisory Committee on Civil Disorders--Misc newsletters [News releases] [2/2], 12/1967-01/1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Papers, 1968 [1/2] (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Papers, 1968 [2/2] (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Papers, 1969 [1/2] (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Papers, 1969 [2/2] (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Papers--The Black Panthers, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  General note
  "The Black Panthers" Editor, Patricia Sachs; Text by J. Alvin Kugelmass; Designed by Tuba Studios
- Papers, 1970 [1/3] (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Papers, 1970 [2/3] (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Papers, 1970 [3/3] (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Papers, 1971 [1/2] (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Papers, 1971 [2/2] (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Papers, 1972 [1/2] (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Papers, 1972 [2/2] (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Papers--Ms. magazine, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  "Ms.: The New Magazine for Women" Spring/72 Preview Issue
- Papers--Nixon Made Perfectly Clear, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  "Nixon Made Perfectly Clear" A Rodney Book
- Papers--Skyjak, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  "Skyjak" by ezra [sic]
- Papers, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Papers, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Papers, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Images--Photographs--Poor People's Campaign, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Photographs are blurry.
- Images--Negatives--Poor People's Campaign, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Images are blurry.
- Images--Slides--Pentagon demonstration, 11/1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Images--Slides--Pentagon demonstration, 11/1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Images--Slides--Pentagon demonstration, 11/1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Images--Slides--Pentagon demonstration, 11/1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Slides--Images--Pentagon demonstration, 11/1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Images--Slides--Pentagon demonstration, 11/1967 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Images--Slides--Pentagon demonstration, 11/1967 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Images--Slides--Pentagon demonstration, 11/1967 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Images--Slides--Pentagon demonstration, 11/1967 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Textiles--Legal Aide signs, armbands (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Three hand-drawn signs on white fabric reading "Legal" or "Legal Aide"; One hand-drawn armband reading "Legal"
- Oversize Papers--Life Magazine Special Edition Woodstock Music Festival, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Oversize papers, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Oversize papers, 04/1971-05/1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Oversize papers, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Oversize papers (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Buttons, 1968 ca. --1975 ca. (Carton 11, Box 6)
- Buttons, 1968 ca. --1975 ca. (Carton 11, Box 7)
- Buttons, 1968 ca. --1975 ca. (Carton 11, Box 8)
- Buttons, 1968 ca. --1975 ca. (Carton 11, Box 9)
- Sound recording: Eldridge Cleaver, "Soul on Wax", 1968 (Box SHARED Box 28, Box Original Individual Box 10, Folder 1)
- Sound recording: Albert Einstein, Bertrand Russell: "Notice to the World ...renounce war or perish! ...world peace or universal death!" (Box SHARED Box 28, Box Original Individual Box 10, Folder 2)
- Sound recording: "Guilt" His or Ours; Fight for Peace, War is the Price of Apathy (Box SHARED Box 28, Box Original Individual Box 10, Folder 3)